DOMINIC DECICCO

WEB DEVELOPER

347-697-2081
Bronx, NY
ddecicco330@gmail.com
dominicdecicco.io
github.com/ddecicco330web
linkedin.com/in/dominicdecicco

SUMMARY

Web with a background in education and game development. Experience in developing databases, tools, and AI for teams.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-End

- HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript
- Libraries / Frameworks (React, Redux, Angular, Angular Material, Bootstrap, jQuery)
- TDD & BDD
- Mobile Apps (React Native, Expo, PWA)
- Responsive Design

Back-End

- Node.js & Express
- API (RESTful, JSON, Postman)
- AWS
- MongoDB, Firebase

EDUCATION

CareerFoundry

Certificate in Full-Stack Development

Completed February 2024

Intensive project-based online training focused on HTML, CSS, Javascript, and most popular libraries and frameworks (React, React Native, Angular, etc.).

Full Sail University

BS in Game Development

Completed August 2015

FULLSTACK PROJECTS

Personal Project, CareerFoundry

Recipes

Feburary 2024 - March 2024

- Implemented Django and PostgreSQL to store recipe and user information.
- Built the front end using CSS, Python, and Django to allow the user to search for, create, update, and delete recipes.
- Utilized AWS S3 to let users upload recipe images.
- Visualized information using MatPlotLib.

Personal Project, CareerFoundry

myFlix

September 2023 - November 2023

- Created a relational database using MongoDB to store user, movie, director, actor, and genre information.
- Built a RESTful API with Node.js and Express, using Mongoose to interact with the database.
- Tested API using Postman and deployed the API with Heroku.
- Created two responsive front-end applications. One using React,
 React Bootstrap, and JSX, and another using Angular, Angular
 Material, and TypeScript. Users can create an account, update their
 information, browse movies, and update their favorite movies list.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sky Language School

English Instructor

August 2023 - Present

- Instructed adult ESL students on various aspects of the English language like vocabulary, grammar, speaking, writing, reading, and listening comprehension.
- Developed lesson plans tailored to the learning goals of the students.
- Ensured students enjoyed classes which led to all of the students reporting great satisfaction with the classes and applying their skills to pass standardized tests.

POLY

English Instructor

February 2020 - April 2023

- Instructed kindergarten and elementary ESL students to improve speaking, writing, reading, and listening skills.
- Presented course material in a clear, understandable, and enjoyable way to ensure students retain the information and skills learned from the class.
- Ensured excellent student comprehension which led to the students consistently scoring higher than the school average on monthly comprehension tests with a class average of above 90%.